# Jyoti Yadav Junior Software Developer

## PERSONAL INFO



iyoti.yadav2508@gmail.com

**+49 152 571 44662** 

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jyotiyadav2508/

https://github.com/jyotiyadav2508

### PERSONAL PROFILE

Currently completing diploma in Full Stack Software Development from Code Institute. With combination of my Masters in Mathematics, teaching experience and recently acquired programming and analytical skills, I see myself as a good fit for career in software technology. I have been honing my skills in software technology for the last 5 months. With proficiency in HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Python, I am looking forward to start my career in the tech industry, where I can learn and apply my knowledge to create a win-win situation for the company and my professional career growth.

#### **KEY SKILLS**

Languages Frameworks Version Control **Programming Tools** 

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python Bootstrap, Flask, Django GitHub, Git, Heroku **VS Code** Other Tools

Lucid Chart (for Flow chart), Balsamiq (for wireframe)

### **EDUCATION & TRAINING**

Full Stack Web Development Diploma (Ongoing) Jul 2022 - Jul 2023

Code Institute - Online

Jan 2020 - Jan 2022 German - B2 Level

iQ Sprachschule - TELC Certificate

Jan 2016 - Jun 2016 Government Teacher Qualification (Post Graduate Teacher - Mathematics)

Self-Preparation

Jul 2012 - Feb 2014 Government Teacher Qualification (Trained Graduate Teacher - Mathematics)

Self-Preparation

Jun 2010 - Jun 2012 Masters of Science - Mathematics (2,2)

Banasthali University, Rajasthan, India

PORTFOLIO PROJECT

Yoga-Lovers Interactive Yoga website. **Technologies Used:** HTML, CSS.

GitHub: https://github.com/jyotiyadav2508/Yoga-Lovers

Game Rock-Scissor-Paper Interactive game. Technologies Used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript.

GitHub: https://github.com/jyotiyadav2508/Game-Rock-Scissors-Paper

Pizza-Hub Menu based Pizza delivery platform. **Technology Used**: Python, Google sheets

API, Heroku. GitHub: https://github.com/jyotiyadav2508/pizza-hub

01.12.2022 Page 1 / 2

# Jyoti Yadav Junior Software Developer

**WORK EXPERIENCE** 

Jan 2019 - Dec 2019 Relocation to Germany

Aug 2017 - Dec 2018 Maternity Leave

Apr 2016 - Jul 2017 School Teacher – Mathematics

CD Foundation, Gurugram, India

Jan 2015 - Dec 2015 Maternity Leave

PERSONAL SKILLS

Mother tongue(s) Hindi

Foreign language(s)

**UNDERSTANDING SPEAKING WRITING** Spoken Spoken Listening Reading interaction production **B2 B**2 B2 B2 B2 B2 C1 B2 B2 C1

German English

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user - B1 and B2: Independent user - C1 and C2: Proficient user

Common European Framework of Reference for Languages

JOB-RELATED SKILLS Fast Learner

Good analytical skills

Team work UX Design

OTHER TOOLS Microsoft Office, Slack

ADDITIONAL INFO Participated in Hackathon in November 2022 to develop project on music-based

theme arranged by Code Institute

01.12.2022 Page 2/2